Guide to the Rose Goldsen papers, [ca. 1950-1985]
Goldsen, Rose papers, [ca. 1950-1985]
- Series VI Subject Files
  - Alphabetical Subject Files
    - NON-VERBAL Communication And The Senses
      - PONS Test - Describing Wordless Messages (Box 29, Folder 64)
      - Retarded, Disabled People (Box 29, Folder 65)
      - Ritual, Subliminal Cues (Box 29, Folder 66)
      - Sensation and Timing - RKG Broadcasts and Columns (Box 29, Folder 67)
        5 radio scripts 12/6/77 - 11/4/79; 2 Grapevine articles 11/79
      - Sensory Deprivation (Box 29, Folder 68)
      - Senssurround, "Earthquake" (Box 29, Folder 69)
      - Sleep Lab (Box 29, Folder 70)
      - Sign Language (Box 29, Folder 71)
      - Smell (Box 29, Folder 72)
      - Smell - Appleton Papers, Inc. (Box 29, Folder 73)
      - Smell - Scratch & Sniff (Box 29, Folder 74)
      - Smell and Taste - International Flavor and Fragrance (Box 29, Folder 75)
      - Sound and Noise (Box 29, Folder 76)
      - Storytelling, Bunraku (Box 29, Folder 77)
      - Taste (Box 29, Folder 78)
      - Touching (Box 29, Folder 79)
      - TV for the Deaf (Box 29, Folder 80)
      - Vision and Images (Box 29, Folder 81)
      - Voice Analysis (Box 29, Folder 82)
      - Voice and Language (Box 29, Folder 83)
      - White House - Tapes, TV Image (Box 29, Folder 84)
    - No TV: Cases (Box 29, Folder 85)
      RKG radio script 12/9-12/78
    - Nutrition Paradigm
      - Index to Nutrition File (Partial) (Box 29, Folder 86)
    - Nutrition: Indexed Folders
      - Advertising (Box 29, Folder 87)
      - Food Prices (Box 29, Folder 88)
      - Shift in Eating Habits (Box 29, Folder 89)
      - John Hess (Box 29, Folder 90)
        Letter to RKG
      - Food in History: Tannahill (Box 29, Folder 91)
        2/28/75
      - Lactose and Lactase (Box 29, Folder 92)
      - Food Fads and Taboos (Box 29, Folder 93)
      - Food Production System (Box 29, Folder 94)
      - Mechanization of Fruits and Vegetables (Box 29, Folder 95)
      - Galbraith: United Fruit (Box 29, Folder 96)
      - Additives, Regulation, Standards (Box 29, Folder 97)
        RKG letter to Elizabeth Linuss 8/6/71; notes 1p
      - Hearing before Select Committee on Nutrition and Human Needs (Box 29, Folder 98)
    - Nutrition: Un-Indexed Files
      - Breast Feeding/Infant Formula (Box 29, Folder 99)
      - Breast Feeding/Infant Formula -Nestle (Box 29, Folder 100)
      - Foods and Flavors (Box 29, Folder 101)
      - Nutrition and Food Production -Unclassified (Box 29, Folder 102)
      - Nutrition Education - 1973 Senate Hearings (Box 29, Folder 104)
      - Nutrition - Experts' Reports (Box 29, Folder 104)
    - Office Systems (Box 29, Folder 105)
    - Oil Companies (Energy Issues)
      - Advertisements and Advertising Policy (Box 29, Folder 106)
      - Advertisements - Mobil (Box 29, Folder 107)
      - Acquisitions/Mergers (Box 29, Folder 108)
      - Charter Oil (Box 29, Folder 109)
      - Exxon (Box 29, Folder 110)
      - Mobil 's Fallen Sparrow Ad -Religious Themes (Box 29, Folder 111)
      - Oil Companies - Unclassified (Box 29, Folder 112)
      - Oil Crisis Pre-1979 (Box 29, Folder 113)
      - Pricing/Tax 1979 (Box 29, Folder 114)
      - Sponsorship of TV Programs (Box 29, Folder 115)
    - Olympics 1980, 1984
      - Moscow 1980 (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Olympics - unclassified (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Polititians, Public Figures, And Show Business
      - Citizenry as Audience (Box 30, Folder 3)
        RKG radio script draft 8/24-6/74; notes c 10pp
      - Henry Kissinger (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Political Broadcasting (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Political Campaigns and TV (Box 30, Folder 6)
      - Politicians as Celebrities (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - Showbiz Politics (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Polls And Polling
      - AIPO Questions/ABC Research (Box 30, Folder 9)
        Letter from Ellen [Franklin] (ABC employee) 6/20/79
      - Robert T. Bower, Television and the Public (Box 30, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence (Box 30, Folder 11)
        1973-74
      - RKG Lecture Notes (Box 30, Folder 12)
        C 40pp
      - RKG Notes - Additional (Box 30, Folder 13)
        c 10pp; letter to "Broth" 9/15/73
      - Institute for Social Research -Newsletter (Box 30, Folder 14)
      - Political Science Paradigm (Box 30, Folder 15)
      - Polling - Discussion and Analysis (Box 30, Folder 16)
      - Polls - Examples (Box 30, Folder 17)
      - Supporting Data (Box 30, Folder 18)
      - Voting (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Pornography, Sexuality And Taboos
      - Availability of Porn, Zoning (Box 30, Folder 20)
        Student notes on porn in Ithaca stores 1976
      - Cannibalism (Box 30, Folder 21)
      - Children, Pornography and Prostitution (Box 30, Folder 22)
      - Crime Linked to Pornography (Box 30, Folder 23)
      - Death (Box 30, Folder 24)
      - Deep Throat, Linda Lovelace (Box 30, Folder 25)
      - Examples (Box 30, Folder 26)
      - Films (Box 30, Folder 27)
      - Financial Considerations (Box 30, Folder 28)
      - RKG Broadcasts (Box 30, Folder 29)
      - RKG Notes on Pornography (9pp) (Box 30, Folder 30)
        14 radio scripts 9/3-11/79
      - Homosexuality, Transvestitism, Transsexual ity (Box 30, Folder 31)
      - Hustler Magazine, Larry Flynt (Box 30, Folder 32)
      - Incest - "Luna" (Box 30, Folder 33)
      - Incest - NEC Weekend Show, 5/77 (Box 30, Folder 34)
      - Incest - Unclassified (Box 30, Folder 35)
      - International Pornography (Box 30, Folder 36)
      - The Left and Porno (Box 30, Folder 37)
      - Legitimation of Pornography (Box 30, Folder 38)
      - Media Advertisements (Box 30, Folder 39)
      - Opponents of Pornography (Box 30, Folder 40)
      - Playboy Magazine - 1974 (Box 30, Folder 41)
      - Playboy Magazine - 1979 (Box 30, Folder 42)
      - Pornography and Sexuality -Unclassified (Box 30, Folder 43)
      - Pornography for Women (Box 30, Folder 44)
      - Pornography Magazines for Men (Box 30, Folder 45)
      - Production Process (Box 30, Folder 46)
      - Prostitution (Box 30, Folder 47)
      - Racial Symbols and Pornography (Box 30, Folder 48)
      - Elizabeth Ray - Wayne Hays caper (Box 30, Folder 49)
      - Reverential Symbols (Bible, National Anthem, etc.) (Box 30, Folder 50)
      - Rock Music (Box 30, Folder 51)
      - Sex and Sexuality (Box 30, Folder 52)
      - Sex as Work (Box 30, Folder 53)
      - Snuff Films (Box 30, Folder 54)
      - Deborah Spray - "Stack O Wheat Murders" (Box 30, Folder 55)
        Letter to RKG by "Deborah Spray" (Nikki Craft), nd
      - Totalitarian Symbols and Porno (Box 30, Folder 56)
      - TV Pornography (Box 30, Folder 57)
      - TV - Sexual Innuendos Infiltrate Prime Time (Box 30, Folder 58)
    - Presidential Administrations
      - Carter Administration (Box 30, Folder 59)
      - Reagan Administration (Box 30, Folder 60)
    - Production And Syndication
      - Ad Agencies as Producers (Box 30, Folder 61)
      - Co-Production Deals (Box 30, Folder 62)
      - How a Production is Made and Who Makes It (Box 30, Folder 63)
      - Network Programming Decisions, Pilot Shows (Box 30, Folder 64)
      - Production and Syndication -Unclassified (Box 30, Folder 65)
      - Syndication (Box 30, Folder 66)
    - Production Companies
      - Chuck Berris Productions (Box 30, Folder 67)
      - Cross productions, tie-ins, X-plugs (Box 30, Folder 68)
      - Jaws - production companies tie-ins and plugging (Box 30, Folder 69)
      - Norman Lear - "Dialogue on Film" (Box 30, Folder 70)
      - Osmond Family Interests (Box 30, Folder 71)
      - Production Companies -Unclassified (Box 30, Folder 72)
      - Software Production Analysis and how it works (Box 30, Folder 73)
      - TVTV (Box 30, Folder 74)
      - Warner Communications (Box 30, Folder 75)
    - Production Process
      - Introvision, Live-A-Matics (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - Magicam (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - Mini -Cameras (Box 31, Folder 3)
      - Production Process - Unclassified (Box 31, Folder 4)
      - 3-D films, TV (Box 31, Folder 5)
      - Time Compression, Slow Motion, Variable Speech Control (Box 31, Folder 6)
        Azriel Bibliowicz letter to RKG 10/9/74; RKG notes c 10pp
      - Video Replaces Film (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Program By Program Inventories And Summaries (alphabetical by title)
      - A-C (Box 31, Folder 8)
      - Dallas (Box 31, Folder 9)
      - D-G (Box 31, Folder 10)
      - H-L (Box 31, Folder 11)
      - M (Box 31, Folder 12)
      - N-P (Box 31, Folder 13)
      - R-S (Box 31, Folder 14)
      - "Soap" (Box 31, Folder 15)
      - Star Trek (Box 31, Folder 16)
      - Superman (Box 31, Folder 17)
        Radio script, "Legitimating the One-Night Stand (ABC's 'Taxi')" 3/3-6/79
      - T (Box 31, Folder 18)
      - U-W (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Program Schedules Strategy
      - Children's Programs (Box 31, Folder 20)
      - Daytime - Incl. Daytime International (Box 31, Folder 21)
      - Primetime 9/78 - 9/79 (Box 31, Folder 22)
      - Primetime 9/79 (Box 31, Folder 23)
      - Primetime 9/79 - Production Companies, Cost per Episode (Box 31, Folder 24)
      - Primetime 1980 (Box 31, Folder 25)
      - Primetime 9/80 - 9/81 (Box 31, Folder 26)
      - Primetime 9/81 - 9/82 (Box 31, Folder 27)
      - Primetime 1982-83 (Box 31, Folder 28)
      - Program Schedules - Unclassified (Box 31, Folder 29)
    - Programming Strategy
      - Miniseries (Box 31, Folder 30)
      - Bruce Owen et al - "The Television Rivalry Game" (Box 31, Folder 31)
      - Puerto Rico TV (Box 31, Folder 32)
      - Programming Strategy -Unclassified (Box 31, Folder 33)
      - Series and Spinoffs (Box 31, Folder 34)
      - Sexy Programs (Box 31, Folder 35)
    - Proprietary Learning Systems
      - McDonald's Action Packs (Box 31, Folder 36)
        RKG, "Corporate School Text Packs Ithaca Times, 2/15- 79; Steven Klees letter to RKG 2/14/77
      - Proprietary Education -Unclassified (Box 31, Folder 37)
      - SRA Learning Dynamics (Box 31, Folder 38)
        Radio Script 9/20-23/75. SRA= Scientific Research Associates
      - Xerox Education (Box 31, Folder 39)
        RKG letters re: Carnegie Commisssion
    - Public Broadcasting
      - Advertisers Use Public Broadcasting (Box 31, Folder 40)
      - Advocacy: WQLN, AIM, Pacifica (Box 31, Folder 41)
      - Carnegie Commission Report (Box 31, Folder 42)
        RKG letters re: Carnegie Commission
      - NPR (National Public Radio) (Box 31, Folder 43)
      - Public TV (Box 31, Folder 44)
    - Public Interest & Pressure Groups
      - Action for Children's Television (ACT) (Box 31, Folder 45)
      - Broadcasting Law and the Consumer (Box 31, Folder 46)
      - Center for Non-Broadcast Television (Box 31, Folder 47)
      - Media Report to Women (Box 31, Folder 48)
      - Morality in Media; National Federation for Decency (Box 31, Folder 49)
      - National Citizens Committee for Broadcasting (Box 31, Folder 50)
      - National Commission on Working Women (NCWW) - Sally Steenland (Box 31, Folder 51)
      - New York Council on Children's Television (Box 31, Folder 52)
      - Public Interest Groups -Unclassified (Box 31, Folder 53)
      - Public Service Satellite Consortium Newsletter (Box 31, Folder 54)
      - WATCH (Washington Association for Television and Children) (Box 31, Folder 55)
    - Publishing Companies
      - Alternative Presses (Box 31, Folder 56)
      - Book Fair 1979 - NYC (Box 31, Folder 57)
      - Book Rights, Copyright Suits (Box 31, Folder 58)
      - Cross Plugging and Tie-ins (Box 31, Folder 59)
        Radio script, "Raggedy Ann and Raggedy Andy," 7/6/77; notes 1p
      - Doubleday - incl. Dell (Box 31, Folder 60)
      - Guyana Massacre, Cults (Box 31, Folder 61)
      - Harpers, Saturday Review (Box 31, Folder 62)
      - Macmillan (Box 31, Folder 63)
      - Magazines (Box 31, Folder 64)
      - Magazines About TV (Box 31, Folder 65)
      - Marketing Strategy (Box 31, Folder 66)
      - Marvel Comics (Box 31, Folder 67)
      - McGraw Hill/American Express (Box 31, Folder 68)
      - Mergers, Acquisitions, Cross-Ownerships (Box 31, Folder 69)
      - Ms. Magazine (Box 31, Folder 70)
      - Murdoch Holdings (NY Magazine; NY Post; Village Voice; Australian Holdings) (Box 31, Folder 71)
      - Newspapers (Box 31, Folder 72)
      - Newspaper Competition (Box 31, Folder 73)
      - Oil Companies - acquisitions (Box 31, Folder 74)
      - Playboy Enterprises (Box 31, Folder 75)
      - Publishing Companies (Box 31, Folder 76)
        RKG, "A Raggedy Ann Blitz." Ithaca New Times, 8/2/77
      - Publishing - Unclassified (Box 31, Folder 77)
      - Readers Digest Interests (Box 31, Folder 78)
      - Romance Novels (Box 31, Folder 79)
      - Time Inc. (Box 31, Folder 80)
      - Video Magazines/Newsletters (Box 31, Folder 81)
      - Warner Inc. (Box 31, Folder 82)
        RKG, "Superman: SuperHype," Ithaca Times, 9/7/78
      - Western Publishing Co. (Box 31, Folder 83)
      - Thomas Whiteside, "The Blockbuster Complex" (Box 31, Folder 84)
      - Writers (Box 31, Folder 85)
      - Zif f-Davis (Box 31, Folder 86)
    - Ratings
      - Alternative and New Ratings Systems (Box 31, Folder 87)
      - Audience Meters (Box 31, Folder 88)
      - Cable Ratings (Box 31, Folder 89)
      - Coverage - Demographics (Box 31, Folder 90)
      - AC Nielsen (Box 31, Folder 91)
      - Radio Ratings Companies (Box 31, Folder 92)
      - Ratings - Unclassified (Box 31, Folder 93)
      - Sweeps (Box 31, Folder 94)
      - Viewing Habits (Box 31, Folder 95)
    - Arbitron
      - Arbitron - Articles, Letters (Box 31, Folder 96)
      - Arbitron Literature -Unclassified (Box 31, Folder 97)
      - Areas of Dominant Influence (ADI's) (Box 31, Folder 98)
      - Binghamton (Box 31, Folder 99)
      - Measuring the Black Population (Box 31, Folder 100)
      - Methodology (Box 31, Folder 101)
      - Radio (Box 31, Folder 102)
      - Television Households Books (Box 31, Folder 103)
    - Reading, Literacy, Orality TV
      - History of Books and Literacy (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - Literacy Today (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - Reading and Literacy -Unclassified (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - TV and Culture (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - TV and Education (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - Word and Image (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - Writing and Speech (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Regulation And Control
      - Cable, Video Deregulation (Box 32, Folder 8)
      - Minorities and Radio Deregulation (Box 32, Folder 9)
      - NY State Assembly Nutritional Ads - Kids (Box 32, Folder 10)
        Ellen Franklin letter to RKG 4/1/77
      - Radio Deregulation (Box 32, Folder 11)
        Radio script 4/2-13/80
      - Regulation - Unclassified (Box 32, Folder 12)
        Radio script, "Double-Billing Deregulation," 7/7-10/79
    - Religion
      - Evangelism, Christian Right (Box 32, Folder 13)
      - Jesus of Nazareth (Box 32, Folder 14)
      - Religion - Unclassified (Box 32, Folder 15)
      - Religious Broadcasting (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Roots
      - Alex Haley: Pre-Broadcast Articles (Box 32, Folder 17)
      - Roots I (Box 32, Folder 18)
      - Roots - Aftermath (Box 32, Folder 19)
      - Roots II (Box 32, Folder 20)
      - Roots - Outreach (Box 32, Folder 21)
      - Roots 1/21-1/30/77 RKG Broadcast Notes (Box 32, Folder 22)
        c 40pp; Radio script draft 1/29-2/1/77
    - Satellites
      - ATS-F: Education Satellite Communications Demonstration (Box 32, Folder 23)
      - Canada (Box 32, Folder 24)
      - Comsat (Box 32, Folder 25)
      - Comsat - Satellite Television Corp. (Box 32, Folder 26)
      - Direct Broadcast Satellites (Box 32, Folder 27)
      - Earth Stations (Box 32, Folder 28)
      - European Satellites (Box 32, Folder 29)
      - FCC Regulation (Box 32, Folder 30)
      - Intelsat (Box 32, Folder 31)
      - Intelsat - Ronnie Schwartz Paper (Box 32, Folder 32)
        Soc 462, Spring 1980
      - Intermedia - IBI (Box 32, Folder 33)
        International Broadcast Institute
      - International Issues (Box 32, Folder 34)
      - Lecture 4/29/80 (Box 32, Folder 35)
      - Medical Uses (Box 32, Folder 36)
      - Military Implications (Box 32, Folder 37)
      - Multi-Point Distribution Systems (MDS) (Box 32, Folder 38)
        RKG notes 2pp; Jim Teicher letter to RKG 2/25/80
      - NASA, Space Shuttle, Skylab (Box 32, Folder 39)
      - Network Project (Box 32, Folder 40)
      - Public Broadcasting (Box 32, Folder 41)
      - RKG Notes (Box 32, Folder 42)
        20pp
      - Satellite Business Systems (SBS) (Box 32, Folder 43)
      - Satellite Systems (Box 32, Folder 44)
      - Satellite to Home (Box 32, Folder 45)
      - Satellite Users (Box 32, Folder 46)
      - Satellites - Overview (Box 32, Folder 47)
      - Satellites - Unclassified (Box 32, Folder 48)
      - Teleconferencing (Box 32, Folder 49)
      - Women's Satellite Communication (Box 32, Folder 50)
    - Satellite Communications In Developing Countries
      - Alaska and Canada (Box 32, Folder 51)
      - Developing Countries - Unclassified (Box 32, Folder 52)
      - Latin America (Box 32, Folder 53)
      - SITE: Satellites for Rural Development (Box 32, Folder 54)
      - A. Sivanandan: "Imperialism in the Silicon Age" (Box 32, Folder 55)
    - Schools And TV (TV's Clients)
      - Critical Viewing Skills (Box 32, Folder 56)
      - Instructional TV and Video (Box 32, Folder 57)
      - Schools, TV, TV's Clients -Unclassified (Box 32, Folder 58)
      - Television Awareness Training (Box 32, Folder 59)
      - TV and College Education (Box 32, Folder 60)
    - Soap Operas
      - Bibliowicz - Latin American Soaps (Box 32, Folder 61)
      - RKG on McNeil/Lehrer Report (Box 32, Folder 62)
        Transcript of 12/25/79 show, featuring RKG
      - Popularity (Box 32, Folder 63)
      - Production System: RKG Notes (Box 32, Folder 64)
        c 50pp
      - Soap Operas - Overview (Box 32, Folder 65)
      - Soap Operas - Unclassified (Box 32, Folder 66)
    - Space Communication (Box 32, Folder 67)
    - Subscription TV
      - Metromedia vs. American Satellite Network (ASN) (Box 32, Folder 68)
      - National Subscription Television ("ON TV") (Box 32, Folder 69)
      - STV/SMATV (Box 32, Folder 70)
    - Suicide (Box 32, Folder 71)
      RKG notes 17pp
    - Technology And Culture - Social Policy
      - Appropriate Technology (Box 32, Folder 72)
      - Computers (Box 32, Folder 73)
      - Conference - Technology: Over the Invisible Line? 3/19-22/80 (Box 32, Folder 74)
        RKG notes c 50pp
      - Failsafe (Box 32, Folder 75)
      - RKG Notes on Technology and Culture (Box 32, Folder 76)
      - History of Technology (Box 32, Folder 77)
      - Jerry Mander Lecture 5/3/79 (Box 32, Folder 78)
        RKG notes 12pp
      - Metric System (Box 32, Folder 79)
      - Military Technology (Box 32, Folder 80)
      - Politics of Technology (Box 32, Folder 81)
      - Scientists, "Experts" (Box 32, Folder 82)
      - Technology and Culture -Unclassified (Box 32, Folder 83)
      - Technology and Values (Box 32, Folder 84)
      - Technology is Not Neutral (Box 32, Folder 85)
      - Technology is Not Neutral - Ivan Ilich (Box 32, Folder 86)
      - Third World (Box 32, Folder 87)
      - Workplace (Box 32, Folder 88)
    - Tests and Testing (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Theme Parks - Enterprise Square (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Theoretical Statements And Analysis
      - Art/ Performance/ Culture (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - Folklore and Myth (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - Rose Goldsen - Amherst 11/79 Conference Leftovers (Box 33, Folder 5)
      - RKG Notes on Discussion with Max Black - Paradigms, Causality and Evolution. 1973 (Box 33, Folder 6)
      - RKG Notes on Invisibility of Cultural Norms (Box 33, Folder 7)
        6pp
      - Language (Box 33, Folder 8)
      - Mass Media (Box 33, Folder 9)
      - Philosophy of Science (Box 33, Folder 10)
      - Political/Social Organization (Box 33, Folder 11)
      - Politics and Communication (Box 33, Folder 12)
      - Social Environment (Box 33, Folder 13)
      - Social Science (Box 33, Folder 14)
      - Television Environment (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Time
      - RKG Comments on MacLuhan and Organization of the Senses (Box 33, Folder 16)
      - Media Define Time and Experience (Box 33, Folder 17)
      - Time - Unclassified (Box 33, Folder 18)
        RKG letter to Azriel Bibliowicz
      - TV: Changing Our Notions of Time (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - Toy Companies
      - Aurora Products (Box 33, Folder 20)
      - Aviva (Box 33, Folder 21)
      - Binney and Smith (Crayola) (Box 33, Folder 22)
      - Bobbs-Merrill Company (Box 33, Folder 23)
      - Castle Rock Toys (Box 33, Folder 24)
      - Collegeville Costumes (Box 33, Folder 25)
      - Colorforms (Box 33, Folder 26)
      - Disney (Box 33, Folder 27)
      - Fisher-Price Toys (Box 33, Folder 28)
      - GAP Corporation (Box 33, Folder 29)
      - Hasbro (Box 33, Folder 30)
      - H-G Toys (Box 33, Folder 31)
      - Hongkong Toys (Box 33, Folder 32)
      - Ideal (Box 33, Folder 33)
      - Invicta (MasterMind) (Box 33, Folder 34)
      - Kamar (Box 33, Folder 35)
      - Lakeside Games (Box 33, Folder 36)
      - LEGO (Box 33, Folder 37)
      - Lesney (Matchbox) (Box 33, Folder 38)
      - Licensing Companies (Box 33, Folder 39)
      - LJN Toys (Box 33, Folder 40)
      - Mattel Toys (Box 33, Folder 41)
      - Milton Bradley 148 (Box 33, Folder 42)
      - Monogram (Box 33, Folder 43)
      - Osobo (Box 33, Folder 44)
      - Parker Brothers (Box 33, Folder 45)
      - Revel 1 (Box 33, Folder 46)
      - Selchow & Righter (Box 33, Folder 47)
      - Shaper (Box 33, Folder 48)
      - Texas Instruments (Box 33, Folder 49)
      - Tiderider (Box 33, Folder 50)
      - Tomy Corporation (Box 33, Folder 51)
      - Tonka (Box 33, Folder 52)
      - Western Publishing (Box 33, Folder 53)
      - Wham-0 (Box 33, Folder 54)
    - Toys And Games
      - Bibliography - Toys, Children and Advertising (Box 33, Folder 55)
      - Dolls, Fashion Dolls (Box 33, Folder 56)
      - Electronic Games and Toys (Box 33, Folder 57)
      - Rom/Marvel/Mattel (Box 33, Folder 58)
      - Toys and Games - Unclassified (Box 33, Folder 59)
      - Video Games (Box 33, Folder 60)
    - Violence And Violence Research
      - Gerbner, et al: Violence Profiles (Box 33, Folder 61)
      - Lecture (Soc 252) 2/12/80 - Gerbner - Violence (Box 33, Folder 62)
      - Lecture #5 - 2/7/? (Box 33, Folder 63)
      - National Coalition on Television Violence (Box 33, Folder 64)
      - Research - Effects of TV Violence on Children and Teens (Box 33, Folder 65)
      - Robinson: Viewer Perception of TV Violence (Box 33, Folder 66)
        Radio script 6/7-8/80
      - TV, Films, Books (Box 33, Folder 67)
      - Violence Commission (Box 33, Folder 68)
      - Violence Counts (Box 33, Folder 69)
      - Violence - Unclassified (Box 33, Folder 70)
    - Visual Sociology
      - Anthropological Filming (Box 33, Folder 71)
      - Art, Photography (Box 33, Folder 72)
      - Curriculum Design - Semiotics of Images (Summer project by student of Linda Waugh, 1982) (Box 33, Folder 73)
      - Image (Box 33, Folder 74)
      - Television, Film (Box 33, Folder 75)
      - Vision/Color (Box 33, Folder 76)
      - Visual Sociology (Box 33, Folder 77)
  - Conceptual Subject Files
    - Evolution And Habitat
      - Some notes on evolution of physical organisms (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - Human evolution, animal evolution (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - Physical structures are not our only habitat - although they are revealing. (Box 34, Folder 3)
      - Each generation is evolved by & evolves its own habitat (Box 34, Folder 4)
      - Evolution of social loops: examples and RKG notes (Box 34, Folder 5)
      - Umwelt - barn swallows, David in plastic bubble, embryo implants, supermarkets, breastfeeding (Box 34, Folder 6)